In this American English pronunciation video, we're going to learn how to pronounce the AH as in BAT vowel.
在这段美式英语发音视频中，我们将学习如何发音像 BAT 中的 AH 元音。
This is a sound that changes depending on the following sound.
这个音会根据后面的音而变化。
So it can either be a pure vowel or a modified vowel.
所以它可以是一个纯元音或一个修饰元音。
We'll go over both in this video.
我们将在这个视频中讲解这两种情况。
To make the pure AH vowel, the jaw drops quite a bit.
要发出纯 AH 元音，下巴要大幅度下垂。
AH.
AH。
The tip of the tongue stays forward.
舌尖保持向前。
It's touching the back of the bottom front teeth.
它触碰到下前牙的后面。
AH.
AH。
The back part of the tongue stretches up.
舌头的后部向上伸展。
The tongue is wide.
舌头是宽的。
AH.
AH。
Because the tongue is high in the back and low in the front, you can see a lot of it.
因为舌头在后部是高的而在前部是低的，所以你可以看到很多舌头。
This is different from the AH as in FATHER vowel, for example, where the tongue presses down in the back and you see more dark space in the mouth.
这与 FATHER 中的 AH 元音不同，例如，舌头在后部向下压，你会看到嘴里更多的黑暗空间。
AH.
AH。
You can also see the corners of the mouth pull back and up a little bit.
你还可以看到嘴角稍微向后和向上拉。
AH.
AH。
Let's take a look at the pure AH vowel, up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作看看纯 AH 元音。
The tongue tip is down and the back of the tongue lifts.
舌尖向下，舌头的后部抬起。
Here's the word SAT.
这是单词 SAT。
The tongue position is easy to see because of the jaw drop needed for this vowel.
由于这个元音需要下巴下垂，舌头的位置很容易看到。
When AH is in a stressed syllable, the vowel will go up and come down in pitch.
当 AH 在重读音节中时，元音的音调会上升然后下降。
AH.
AH。
SAT.
SAT。
AH.
AH。
In an unstressed syllable, the vowel is flatter and lower in pitch, quieter.
在非重读音节中，元音的音调更平、更低、更安静。
AH.
AH。
This vowel is unstressed in the second syllable of backtrack.
这个元音在 backtrack 的第二个音节中是非重读的。
Let's look up close and in slow motion.
让我们近距离慢动作看看。
In the first stressed syllable, the jaw drops and we see the corners of the lips pull back and up for the stressed AH.
在第一个重读音节中，下巴下垂，我们看到嘴唇的角向后和向上拉以发出重读 AH。
In the unstressed syllable, the jaw drops less.
在非重读音节中，下巴下垂得更少。
Let's compare them.
让我们比较一下。
On top is the stressed AH.
上面是重读 AH。
You can see the jaw drops more.
你可以看到下巴下垂得更多。
For the unstressed AH, the corners of the lips are a little more relaxed than in the stressed version, where they pull slightly back and up.
对于非重读 AH，嘴唇的角比重读版本更放松，重读版本中它们稍微向后和向上拉。
Generally, the unstressed version of a vowel or diphthong is more relaxed and doesn't take the full mouth position.
通常，元音或双元音的非重读版本更放松，不需要完整的口腔位置。
In this case, a little less jaw drop and relaxed lips.
在这种情况下，下巴下垂得更少，嘴唇放松。
This is because unstressed syllables are shorter, so we don't take the time to make the full position.
这是因为非重读音节更短，所以我们没有时间做出完整的位置。
At the beginning of this video, I said the AH vowel is not always a pure AH.
在视频的开头，我说 AH 元音并不总是纯 AH。
This vowel changes when it's followed by a nasal consonant.
当它后面跟着鼻音辅音时，这个元音会改变。
When it's followed by the M or N sounds, the tongue relaxes in the back, making an UH sound after AH.
当它后面跟着 M 或 N 音时，舌头在后部放松，发出 AH 后的 UH 音。
AH.
AH。
It's not a pure AH sound.
这不是一个纯 AH 音。
Unfortunately, this change is not represented in the International Phonetic Alphabet.
不幸的是，这种变化在国际音标中没有表示。
It's still written with the same AH symbol.
它仍然用相同的 AH 符号书写。
So you just have to know when it's followed by M or N, it's different.
所以你只需要知道当它后面跟着 M 或 N 时，它是不同的。
Man.
Man。
Eh.
Eh。
Relaxing the tongue and corners of the lips before the consonant.
在辅音前放松舌头和嘴唇的角。
You can think of this UH relaxation as the UH as in butter sound or schwa sound.
你可以把这种 UH 放松想象成 butter 中的 UH 音或 schwa 音。
Let's look up close and in slow motion at the word EXAM.
让我们近距离慢动作看看单词 EXAM。
First, we see the familiar shape of the mouth when the AH is in a stressed syllable.
首先，我们看到 AH 在重读音节中的熟悉的嘴形。
Watch how the relaxation happens.
看看放松是如何发生的。
The corners of the lips relax in, the tongue will relax down in the back.
嘴唇的角放松，舌头在后部放松。
And the lips close for the M consonant.
嘴唇闭合以发出 M 辅音。
This relaxation of the corner of the lips and back of the tongue happens when the AH vowel is followed by the N consonant as well.
当 AH 元音后面跟着 N 辅音时，嘴唇的角和舌头的后部也会放松。
For example, the word hand.
例如，单词 hand。
Hand.
Hand。
So when you see this symbol followed by this symbol or this symbol, it's no longer a pure AH.
所以当你看到这个符号后面跟着这个符号或这个符号时，它不再是纯 AH。
Think of relaxing out of the vowel.
想象从元音中放松出来。
AH.
AH。
If the next sound is the NG consonant, it's a little different.
如果下一个音是 NG 辅音，那就有点不同。
Rather than AH, the vowel changes into AY.
而不是 AH，元音变成 AY。
It's really like the AY as in SAY diphthong.
这实际上就像 SAY 中的 AY 双元音。
First, the middle part of the tongue lifts towards the roof of the mouth, then the front part of the tongue.
首先，舌头的中部向口腔顶部抬起，然后是舌头的前部。
Let's watch GANG.
让我们看看 GANG。
Up close and in slow motion.
近距离慢动作。
The position for the first sound looks a lot like AH, but the part of the tongue lifting up is more forward.
第一个音的位置看起来很像 AH，但抬起的舌头部分更靠前。
GANG.
GANG。
Then the front part of the tongue arches up towards the roof of the mouth, while the tongue tip remains down.
然后舌头的前部向口腔顶部拱起，而舌尖保持向下。
When you see this symbol followed by this symbol, it's no longer a pure AH.
当你看到这个符号后面跟着这个符号时，它不再是纯 AH。
It's more like AY.
更像 AY。
GANG.
GANG。
Thanks.
Thanks。
Pure stressed AH.
纯重读 AH。
Sat.
Sat。
AH.
AH。
Pure unstressed AH.
纯非重读 AH。
Backtrack.
Backtrack。
AH.
AH。
AH vowel modified by M.
被 M 修饰的 AH 元音。
Exam.
Exam。
AH.
AH。
AH vowel modified by N.
被 N 修饰的 AH 元音。
Man.
Man。
AH.
AH。
AH vowel modified by NG.
被 NG 修饰的 AH 元音。
GANG.
GANG。
AY.
AY。
Example words.
示例单词。
Repeat with me.
跟我重复。
Chapter.
Chapter。
AH.
AH。
Chapter.
Chapter。
Can.
Can。
AH.
AH。
Can.
Can。
Act.
Act。
AH.
AH。
Act.
Act。
Last.
Last。
AH.
AH。
Last.
Last。
Bank.
Bank。
AY.
AY。
Bank.
Bank。
Bypass.
Bypass。
AH.
AH。